Guide to the Queers for Economic Justice records, circa 2000-2014.
Queers for Economic Justice
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Queers for Economic Justice records, circa 2000-2014.
7802
Queers for Economic Justice.
13 cubic feet., 4 mapcase folders, 1 rolled poster
Surveys, posters, banners, and records of the organization.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The records of QEJ consist of key documentation of its founding goals and guiding principles, its sources of funding, the involvement of its staff, executive directors, and Board of Directors, its publicity and outreach efforts, and its major projects including the establishment and operation of a shelter for queer people facing homelessness. Together, these files give a detailed look at the ideas, actions, challenges, and successes of this innovative organization devoted to racial, economic, gender, and sexual equality over its dozen years of operation.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Formed in 2002 in New York City, Queers for Economic Justice (QEJ) was a "progressive non-profit organization committed to promoting economic justice in a context of sexual and gender liberation." As described on its website, its goal was "to challenge and change the systems that create poverty and economic injustice in our communities, and to promote an economic system that embraces sexual and gender diversity." Distinctive among LGBTQI groups at the time in its foregrounding of poverty and class, QEJ introduced different solutions to the national discussion of the queer agenda. On the local level, it spearheaded changes in New York City laws and policies affecting homeless transgender people and gave tangible assistance to the City's queer people in poverty. Its work policies and staff reflected its commitment to being "multi-racial, multi-classed, multi-cultural group of people of diverse marginalized sexual and gender identities, as well as diverse ages, skills, educational levels, backgrounds and abilities."
In 2006, while substantial political effort focused on attaining marriage equality, QEJ brought together twenty-two activists who crafted a report, later signed by hundreds, that pushed for a wider vision. The report, titled Beyond Same-Sex Marriage: A New Strategic Vision For All Our Families and Relationships, became known as the "Beyond Marriage statement." Over time, QEJ published reports on a variety of topics at the intersection of gender, sexuality, and economic justice, offering perspectives on homelessness and housing, economic justice, immigration, drug laws and public health, marriage and other family forms, and welfare. QEJ's major initiatives included community organizing, research and policy development, leadership training, education, outreach, legal aid and advocacy, and community support groups.
Joseph DeFilippis was QEJ's founding executive director. Subsequent leaders were Kenyon Farrow (2009-2011) and Amber Hollibaugh (2011-2014). Jay Toole served as QEJ's founding and only Shelter Director, leading the organization's work relating to housing and homelessness. Among the other LGBTQ, anti-racism, and anti-poverty activists and scholars engaged with the work of QEJ were Ricky Blum Terry Boggis, Ann Cammett, Aine Duggan, Lisa Duggan, Kenyon Farrow, Monroe France, Felix Gardon, Reina Gossett, Richard Kim, Maureen Lane, Ignacio Rivera, Dean Spade, and Jessica Stern.
Due to financial difficulties, QEJ closed in 2014. The organization's projects in the areas of housing and work continue through Jay's House, a shelter non-profit organization in Brooklyn
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The records of QEJ consist of key documentation of its founding goals and guiding principles, its sources of funding, the involvement of its staff, executive directors, and Board of Directors, its publicity and outreach efforts, and its major projects including the establishment and operation of a shelter for queer people facing homelessness. Together, these files give a detailed look at the ideas, actions, challenges, and successes of this innovative organization devoted to racial, economic, gender, and sexual equality over its dozen years of operation.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Queers for Economic Justice.; Queers for Economic Justice.
Subjects:
Gay liberation movement -- United States.; Gays -- United States -- Economic conditions.; Lesbians -- United States -- Economic conditions.; Bisexuals -- United States -- Economic conditions.; Transsexuals -- United States -- Economic conditions.; Transgender people -- Legal status, laws, etc.; Transgender people -- Economic conditions.; Gay liberation movement; Gays -- Economic conditions; Lesbians -- Economic conditions
Places:
United States
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Boxes 11 and 12 are restricted until 2091.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Foundation of Organization, Bylaws, and Constitution
Box 2-3
Series II. Grants and Foundation Files
Box 1-2, 13
Series III. Board Files
Box 7-8, 11-13
Series IV. Financial Records
Box 10
Series V. Project Files
Box 3-6, 10, 13
Series VI. Welfare Rights and Shelter Director
Box 8-9, 13
Series VII. Students, Volunteer, and Intern Program
Box 9
Series VIII. Publicity
Box 7, Mapcase folders
Series IX. Publications, Packets, and General Information
Box 9-10
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Foundation of Organization, Bylaws, and Constitution
  This series contains the QEJ personnel manual and other items that reveal how the organization operated internally as well as its goals and mission.
  - Certificate of Incorporation, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Charitable Choice Forum (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - QEJ Personnel manual and surveys (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Manhattan Neighborhood Network grant material, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Training (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - QUISGLEYA, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - HR Benefits, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Welfare Made a Difference, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - 501 (c) 3, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Meeting Minutes and Notes, January-October, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 59-68)
  - QEJ retreat, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Astraea, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Personnel Manual (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Grant Letters, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Health Services, 2012 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Third Wave Foundation, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Paul Rapoport Foundation, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - QEJ Executive Director Search, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Grants and Donations (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Search Committee, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Astraea, 2012 (Box 3, Folder 11-12)
  - Mertz-Gilmore, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Stonewall, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - QEJ New Funding Possibilities (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Arcus, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - New York Women's Foundation, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - New York Community Trust, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - New York City HIV Planning Group, 2012 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Calamus, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - New York Women's Foundation Grantee Meeting, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Rapoport Fund, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Union square, 2012 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - DPA Proposal, 2010-2011 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Rapoport, 2012 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - QEJ Contact info, Minutes, Structures (from binder), 2003 (Box 3, Folder 24-25)
  - QEJ Surveys, OSI, Pride '03, Cause Effective, Banner, Name/Logo (from binder), 2003 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Agendas and Minutes, Mission (from binder), 2003 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Binder, "Know Your Rights" (Box 3)
  - Binder, "Raise The Money You Need: Building Your Individual Donor Program", 2006 (Box 3)
  - QEJ History (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Building a Queer Left, 2000-2004 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Series II. Grants and Foundation Files
  QEJ obtained funding from numerous sources, including the Astraea Lesbian Foundation, Ben and Jerry's, Gill Foundation, Jewish Fund for Justice, New York Community Trust, New York Women's Foundation, Stonewall Foundation, Unitarian Universalists, and the Paul Rapoport Foundation whose records are preserved at Cornell.
  - DOH Reimbursements, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Union Square, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Open Society Institute (OSI), 2011 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Public Welfare Foundation, 2003-2010 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Paul Rapoport, 2005-2010 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Mary Gryton (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Contains QEJ clue envelopes
  - Buddy Fund, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Drug Policy Alliance, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Funding Exchange, 2003-2009 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Astraea Lesbian Foundation, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Astraea Lesbian Foundation, 2004-2007 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - BW Bastion Foundation, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Arcus, 2006-2009 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Abelard Foundation, 2006-2009 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - New York Foundation, 2004-2007 (Box 1, Folder 15-16)
  - Northstar Site, 2003-2007 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Fund for a Just Society, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Progressive Technology Project, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Veatch, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Colin Higgins, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Jewish Fund for Justice, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Ludwick Family Foundation (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Stonewall Community Foundation, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Unitarian Universalist Funding Program (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Union Square Awards, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Cause Effective, 2003-2005 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Fundraiser/funder (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Letters of recommendation, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - New York Community Trust, 2007-2010 (Box 1, Folder 30-31)
  - New Voices, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - International Center for Tolerance, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - New York Foundation site visit, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - NYU Social Justice, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - NYS LGBT HHSN Technical Assistance, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Ben and Jerry's, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Jill J. Compassion Fund, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Stonewall Foundation, 2006-2007, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 39-40)
  - Sparkplug Foundation, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Tom Duane, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Tides, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Union Square Awards, 2004-2010 (Box 1, Folder 44-45)
  - Valentine Perry Snyder, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - NYC Gay-Lesbian Anti-Violence Project, 2002-2004 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Horizons, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Open Society Institute, 2002, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - RESIST, 2003, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Open Meadow, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Foundation Planning/Prospects, 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Foundation Center Handouts, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Legislative Award, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - New York OCFS, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - New York Women's Foundation, 2003-2007 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Lily Auchincloss Foundation, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Needmor Fund, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Gill Foundation, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Leadership for a Changing World, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Rejection Letters, 2003-2005 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Potential Donors (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Application for a letter of agreement, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - NYS Assembly, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - City Council, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Tax, benefits, and government documents, 2007-2012 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Proposals, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Current Deliverables, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Stonewall Grant, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Fundraising, 2012-2013 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - City HIV (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Current Deliverables, 2009-2011 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Grants (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Certificate of Incorporation, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - LOI's (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - New York Women's Foundation, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Foundation information, 2007-2012 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - QEJ Prospective Funders, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - New York Women's Foundation Hurricane Sandy Grant Report, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Current Deliverables, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Samuel Rubin Foundation, 2013 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Development, 2004-2006 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Marble Church Grant--Miles Goff, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - NYS Grant, 2009-2010 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Major Donors, 33 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - NASI Grant, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - DOH Grant, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - NASI and Union Square, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Award Letters, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - QEJ Donors, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Shelter Safety Campaign, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - New York Women's Foundation Proposal, 2012-2013 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - ARCUS/Trish draft, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Astraea, 2012-2013 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Fundraising Committee, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Miller-Wehrie Family Foundation, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - North Star Fund, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Mertz-Gilmore, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Third Wave Foundation, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - RWJF, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Tides (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Grant applications (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Materials on QEJ from Terry Boggis (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Series III. Board Files
  Board agendas and minutes give top-level insight into the plans and operations of an organization. These begin in December 1999 and are fairly complete.
  - Welfare Warriors shelter surveys, 2007 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Board Packet (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Mailing lists (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Board/Next steps/Merger, etc, 2010 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Board List (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Major Donor Party Information (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Notes to Financial Statements, 2009 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Board meeting notes and agenda, 2010 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - LGBT Health Coalition/board agenda, 2010 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Board members, information, lease contract, 2004, 2010 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Funder briefing, meeting minutes, 2011, 2013 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Financial meetings, 2012 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - ARI Development, 2013 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - New Funding, 2012 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Meeting notes and information, 2001-2002 (Box 7, Folder 35-43)
  - Network and Coalition file (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Pride Planning meeting, May, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Meeting notes, April, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Board nominees, meeting minutes, agendas, and notes, 2003-2005, 2010 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Meeting notes, May-June, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 48-49)
  - Phone Manual (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Board Minutes, 2009 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Somjen suggestions, 2010 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - OCT Board Materials (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Board meeting minutes, February-November, 2011 (Box 7, Folder 54-58)
  - Funder briefing and notes (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Board minutes, 2007, 2013 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Transition (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Board plans and policies, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Worker's Comp, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Board Agenda, 2011 (Box 8, Folder 3-4)
  - Nominee forms (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - QEJ Network (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Board policies and agendas, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - QEJ Network (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Finances and Agendas, 2010 (Box 8, Folder 9-10)
  - Meeting minutes and agenda, December, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Facilitator Agenda, site descriptions, LGBT pamphlets and schedules, 2010 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Meeting minutes, agendas, January-March, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 13-15)
  - Reauthorization: Senate meetings (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Meeting notes and agendas, 2003-2004 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Reports and minutes (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Steering Committee information and ideas, 2001-2003 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Board agendas and information, 2010-2012 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Packing slips and copies of checks (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Personnel files, sign-in sheets, and tax documents [RESTRICTED] (Box 11)
  - Personnel files, sign-in sheets, and tax documents [RESTRICTED] (Box 12)
- Series IV. Financial Records
  Budget materials are in this series, along with miscellaneous files that might rightfully belong in other series, including speeches, conferences, and information on programs and an affordable housing rally.
  - Social Security City Council Hearing, 2005 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Philadelphia Bar Association, 2005 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Conferences, speeches (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Domestic Partners in Shelters (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Affordable Housing Rally (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Election Town Hall Meeting, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Program information, 2006-2011 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - CORI/Bookkeepers, 2010 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Landlord dispute, 2013 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - N. Cheng, 2011 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Audits, 2008-2009 (Box 10, Folder 17-18)
  - Mailing list (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Lease, 2012 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Lease and consultant agreement, receipt, 2010-2011 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Budget notes, meeting minutes, tax information, 2005-2006 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - NYS Department of Labor, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Income reports, 2004-2005 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Income and expense reports, 2004-2005 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Budget, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Budget, 2006 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Audit, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - WWRC Resource Guide (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - IRS, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Sierra admin job description (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Lila interview about LGBT aging (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - YWCA/QEJ coalition (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Building meeting, 2011 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Pride at Work, 2010 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Sex worker statements, 2011 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Phone banking document and lists, 2013 (Box 10, Folder 37-38)
  - QEJ projects (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Black and Pink agreement, 2012 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Faith and Labor Project (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - FIERCE/Building incident, 2011 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Whitehouse conference on Housing and Astraea forms, 2012 (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Rapoport building work (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence on blog posts, copies of articles, 2006 (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - QEJ Network: DYCD (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - HIV Ban, 2007 (Box 10, Folder 47)
- Series V. Project Files
  These files document the core work QEJ did, including sharing their insight and knowledge at Creating Change, the annual activist conference hosted by the National LGBT Task Force. There is good documentation of the annual Amazingly Queer Race for Economic Justice, a “scavenger hunt across the city, in which competing teams will raise funds to combat poverty, homelessness and other urban injustices.”
  There are three folders about the working group that wrote Beyond Same-Sex Marriage: A New Strategic Vision For All Our Families and Relationships, and these shed light on how the marriage summit came to be and the behind-the-scenes thinking about it.
  - Pages from meeting brainstorming (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Shelter Safety Project (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Sheets from a workshop QEJ convened, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Class and Queer Agenda Making, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Creating Change Conference and Class Institute docs, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Welfare Queens (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Institute (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Corporate Funding, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Group Feedback, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - The Amazingly Queer Race clues and information, 2012 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Amazing Race for Economic Justice (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Corporate Welfare project sheets (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Creating Change, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Institute, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - General C.C. Info (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Creating Change, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Workshop, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Creating Change, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - "The Nation" marriage and welfare, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Beyond Same-Sex Marriage planning documents for the summit and talking points about the release of the statement, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Barnard College Desiring Change (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Corrupting Justice, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Roundtable on HIV Immigration Ban, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Beyond Iraq, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Connecting Our Communities (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Social Security and Tax Cuts Forum, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Gay Gentrification, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - State of Homeless, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Occupy the Center, 2004, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Drivers' License policies, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - LGBT HHSN, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Marriage Ala Bush (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Amazing Queer Race team information, 2012 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Amazing Queer Race information, 2012 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Queermazing Race team information (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Amazingly Queer Race, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 18-19)
  - Amazingly Queer Race, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Amazingly Queer Race clues, 2009 (Box 4, Folder 21-22)
  - We're Here, We're Queer, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Amazingly Queer Race, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Amazingly Queer Race, 2007 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Amazingly Queer Race, 2011-2012 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Corporate Funding Workshop, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Spring Mailing, team clues, 2012 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Shelter Safety Campaign Intro, 2011-2012 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Shelter Contact numbers, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - LGBT Latina Reproduction Rights Summit, 2012 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Shelter Volunteer Training Materials, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Yvonne McNeil, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Amazing Queer Race lists, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Rockefeller Drug Law/Queer Policy Work/ Cole P. (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - LGBT Faith and Aging, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Practice Spirit/Do Justice, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Roots Gathering, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - NYS Attorney General, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Desiring Change Doc, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - QEJ Organization Docs, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Roots Coalition, 2013 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Creating Change, 2012 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - QEJ MOU, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Senior Service America, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Homeless Over 50: Report Chicago (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Creating Change, 2012 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Desiring Change, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - State of the Homeless and miscellaneous, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Shelter Facilitator Training Folder, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Leadership Development Course (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Shelter Residents meeting (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Shelter Safety Information (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Community Dialogue Analysis, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Welfare Warriors community events, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - General Welfare information (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Volunteer applications (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Article on TANF, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Workshop info, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - National Coalition Building (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - LD Course Articles (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Beyond Same-Sex Marriage, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    July 26, 2006 statement with sections highlighted. Also, pictures of QEJ’s t-shirt.
  - Video/Audio Release, 2010 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Shelter groups photos and information, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Facilitation Training Materials, 2011 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Corporate Crime Wave materials (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Economic Justice, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Creating Change: Class and Sex, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Amazingly Queer Race, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 17-18)
  - Creating Change: Queer Agenda, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Economic Justice, 2011 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Cash logs (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Stipend reimbursement (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Welfare Course sign-in, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Know Your Rights (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Welfare History, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Sound Device Application and Permit, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Fax Cover Sheet (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Upcoming Outreach Opportunities, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Community Speak Out (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - LD Course Planning Materials, 2011 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - The Race, 2011 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - 9/11 Forum (Box 5, Folder 32)